good morning today's video is my
response to the video I watched this
morning which was Richard Wolf's
economic update this one in particular
reparations and forgiving student debts
which he talks about in there because
this is not anything about actually
reparations or student debt he talks
about uber and how Ober CEO makes a ton
of money and of course the workers don't
his solution for the economy is to
create an economy for the u.s. that is
all worker cooperatives I believe
changing the law because I can't see
happening at any other way where every
workplace has to be a democratic worker
cooperative I've done videos before I'm
why that's not a feasible solution it
takes way too much to implement it as
well as even when it's implemented
they're still competing against each
other so it's not actually efficient and
I'm going to showcase that with the uber
example so let's say after a lot of toil
and labor we get those laws passed and
or you because I'm kind of American you
get those laws passed and now the people
who work for uber and lyft own uber and
lyft they now are still in competition
with each other so they decide in their
workplace that they want to make $25 an
hour's they each make $25 an hour they
were working for $12 an hour under the
old system in uber and lyft so they
slowly though vote their way down to $12
an hour because they were willing to
work for $12 an hour and the consumer
was willing and there is still in
competition with each other and if one
of them is willing to work for 24 or 15
of those 24 35 50 3350 they eventually
get down to the point with like oh this
is the lowest we can go or we're still
able to pay for ourselves because
they're in competition with each other
so you'd have to also pass a clause in
they were like there's one car driving
company and then they set the rate and
then consumers choose to use them or not
they also under that system would never
vote to automotive eeeh khals autonomous
vehicles would take away from their jobs
so they wouldn't want that they're gonna
vote to maintain their work we're in a
new world where
things can be automated as well as with
globalization they the workplace
cooperative would have been a great
solution in the 70s and 80s it's no
longer a great solution although if
there is a worker cooperative user and
lift I will use it in my city I agree
more with using that and supporting
paying them a living wage because the
truth is they could absolutely compete
with lifting and uber if we knew when a
worker cooperative was and wanted to
give them our values because they would
vote to pay 25 dollars an hour we were
do we either use or were already paying
twenty five dollars an hour but instead
of 50% of that or 30% of that going to
to Eber and they still have to maintain
their vehicle and so they end up getting
only $12 an hour we would vote that the
vast majority goes directly to thee to
the driver so that we can use a system
that is more equitable but that is why
consumer cooperative is the answer for
basically everything because a consumer
cooperative overnight we don't need to
wait to change the laws we can just come
together in a city that is that allows
super and left already
Vancouver's not that city and get 10,000
people together who use it and say okay
well let's not have that money go to
shareholders let's create our own
platform because uber doesn't own cars
they don't have driver employees they're
only contractors they don't actually own
anything proprietary we can recreate a
platform that meets our needs that is as
a female has a female driver if I want
that enduring surge pricing is going to
keep more drivers on the car on the road
so we can get home as well as hey I'm
going home from this concert I'm going
to this location in my neighborhood are
there other drivers that us or other
riders that also want to come so that I
can pay less and the driver themselves
can still make a beyond living wage
especially of going during surge pricing
we can create solutions okay so so where
is all that money going for the worker
it's go a lot of it's going to car
maintenance well can we both buy fuel
fuel I don't know can we can we have a
car mechanic that we have vehicles that
are loaned out can we have like what
system can we create that actually
solves all of the problems so more money
is going to the labor and the worker and
we the user would absolutely vote to
have autonomous vehicles because that
would solve a lot of our problems and
when we create an economy where
automation doesn't mean starvation where
everyone's needs are met then we want to
automate because it means there's less
human labor involved and more time to
enjoy everything in life we don't need
users on the road we don't need a
piecemeal economy but as long as we have
a piecemeal economy we might as well own
it together and use it together and
recreate it with the user base in mind
please like and subscribe see you
tomorrow